Diversity Club records, 1887-1969.
Congregational Library & Archives
Diversity Club records, 1887-1969.
RG0024
Congregational Library & Archives
1.09 Cubic Feet
(1 box)
The Diversity Club was founded in 1887 as a club for women who worked at 14 Beacon Street, and they disbanded in 1969. The club hosted dinners, parties, and events with skits and musical comedies. This collection contains meeting minutes, constitutions, financial records, correspondence, songs, poems, scripts, photographs and other memorabilia.
Diversity Club (Boston, Mass.)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was deposited by Grace Ingalls in May, 1969; no accession number.
Historical note
The Diversity Club was founded in 1887 and disbanded in 1969. The club was comprised of a group of women at 14 Beacon Street, who enjoyed hosting parties, dinners, and holiday events. The Diversity Club published the Congregational Tattler, an informational and entertaining news source for the happenings in the building.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes administrative records such as meeting minutes, treasury reports, constitutions, building discussions, and correspondence. This collection also includes programming records such as party invitations, event programs, scripts, stories, songs, and poetry.
Arrangement
Materials have been arranged into the two series listed below. Each series is arranged in chronological order by start date.
Series 1: Administrative records, 1887-1969
Series 2: Programming records, 1887-1950
Correspondence.; Photographs.; Programs; Women -- Societies and clubs.; Diversity Club (Boston, Mass.)
- Administrative records, 1887 1969; 8 Volumes; 13 Folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains administrative records, including meeting minutes, lists of officers, constitutions, building discussions, correspondence, evaluations, financial and treasury reports.
  - Meeting minutes, 1887 1894; 1887-1894 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Separated Materials
    The folder Records, 1893-1931 was separated from this volume.
  - Treasury reports, 1889 1900; 1889-1900 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    The folder Receipts, 1890-1908 was separated from this volume.
  - Receipts, 1890 1908; 1890-1908 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    This folder was separated from the volume Treasury reports, 1889-1900
  - Constitutions, 1892 1938; 1892-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Building discussions, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Records, 1893 1931; 1893-1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    This folder was separated from the volume Meeting minutes, 1887-1894
  - Correspondence, 1893 1937; 1893-1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lists of officers, 1894 1937; 1894-1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meeting minutes, 1895 1904; 1895-1904 (Box 1, Volume 3)
  - Treasury reports, 1900 1913; 1900-1913 (Box 1, Volume 4)
    The folder Records, 1901-1913 was separated from this volume.
  - Records, 1901 1913; 1901-1913 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    This folder was separated from Treasury reports, 1900-1913.
  - Meeting minutes, 1904 1911; 1904-1911 (Box 1, Volume 5)
    The folder Records, 1911-1933 was separated from this volume.
  - Records, 1911 1933; 1911-1933 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    This folder was separated from the volume Meeting minutes, 1904-1911
  - Meeting minutes, 1914 1924; 1914-1924 (Box 1, Volume 6)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1916 1920; 1916-1920 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Meeting minutes, 1924 1936; 1924-1936 (Box 1, Volume 7)
  - Meeting minutes, 1936 1940; 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Evaluations, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Records, 1941 1969; 1941-1945, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Treasury reports, 1942 1945; 1942-1945 (Box 1, Volume 8)
    Receipts 1944-1969 was separated from this bound volume.
  - Receipts, 1944 1969; 1944-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    This folder was separated from Treasury reports, 1942-1945.
- Programming records, 1887 1969; 1887-1950; 10 Folders
  This series contains programming records, including, event planning and programming, party and dinner invitations, and written works like songs, poetry, scripts, and stories.
  - Party invitations and programs, 1887 1905; 1887-1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Scripts and stories, 1887 1910; 1887-1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Songs and poetry, 1887 1937; 1887-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photograph, circa 1890 (Folder 4)
  - 50th anniversary and recollections, 1892 1945; 1892-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 1893, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Book title pun book, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Congregational Tattler, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Party invitations and programs, 1906 1950; 1906-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Menu, undated (Folder 3)